Only monsters play God.
Frankenstein is a drama, fantasy, horror film directed by Guillermo del Toro.
Victor Frankenstein, a brilliant but egotistical scientist, brings a creature to life in a monstrous
experiment that ultimately leads to the undoing of both the creator and his tragic creation.
Victor Frankenstein, played by Oscar Isaac.
The Creature, played by Jacob Elordi.
Harlander, played by Christoph Waltz.
Elizabeth / Claire Frankenstein, played by Mia Goth.
William Frankenstein, played by Felix Kammerer.
Leopold Frankenstein, played by Charles Dance.
Frankenstein is a 2025 American Gothic science fiction drama film produced, written, and
directed by Guillermo del Toro, based on the 1818 novel by Mary Shelley.
The film stars Oscar Isaac as Victor Frankenstein and Jacob Elordi as the
Creature, with Mia Goth and Christoph Waltz in supporting roles.
The story follows the life of Frankenstein, an egotistical scientist whose
experiment in creating new life results in dangerous consequences.
Del Toro had long imagined a faithful Frankenstein film as a "dream project".
This was initially in development for Universal Pictures, with del Toro casting frequent collaborator
Doug Jones as the Creature, and Bernie Wrightson being considered for the monster's design.
However, Universal suspended the project in relation to
its planned Dark Universe franchise.
Netflix revived the project in 2023, with Elordi
instead portraying the Creature.
Filming took place from February to September 2024.
Wrightson had died in 2017, and the illustrated compilation Bernie
Wrightson's Frankenstein was a key inspiration for the film's look.
Frankenstein premiered at the 82nd Venice
International Film Festival on August 30, 2025.
The film was released on Netflix.
It had a limited theatrical release in the United States from October
17 and was globally released on November 7 on Netflix.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics.
Both the National Board of Review and the American Film
Institute named it as one of the top ten films of 2025.
It received five nominations at the 83rd Golden Globe
Awards, including Best Motion Picture – Drama.
It received nine nominations at the 98th Academy Awards, including Best
Picture, Best Adapted Screenplay and Best Supporting Actor (Elordi).
The film explores themes of monster, based on novel or
book, supernatural, surgeon, mad scientist.
The tone is dark and emotional.